Through the benefits, you understand
your target customers. You'll see also
how you do a persona.
Um you test your assumptions, so it's be
it's going to be much easier for you to
discuss uh about them and to say that
yes, these are validated. Users need
this. Um you can uh discover how to do
your business model. So, you'll discover
that if those guys don't pay for it,
then the other guys need to pay for it.
Otherwise, I won't have um profit within
my my company. Finding the product
market fit.
Product market fit is uh the holy grail
of startups. In early stage, your goal
is to fine-tune your product based on
the customer discovery that you do, so
that uh you increase your chances to
achieve this product market fit. And
yeah, you save time and money. That's
super important. What's the most painful
thing, in my opinion, when building
products, when being a builder in
technology, is building something that
will never be used by anyone. That
sucks. If you invest a lot and a lot of
money without getting anything in
return, of course, and you are not
getting good feedback from users. No one
wants to use it. Um
that is bad. So, it will hurt. And it is
better
uh to invest time in talking to users,
building something that matters, and
after and by that saving your your time
investment. And yeah, foster customer
loyalty. As I said, customers are happy
if you make something that they want to
use and that they need, uh not something
that you would uh that they would hate
using.
You will answer this question if they
will buy it or choose to use it, if they
can use it, if you can build it, um if
it works for your business, because you
might discover that this is not
something that you can build or want to
build because you might discuss with
users and realize that what they need
you cannot build or you don't want to
build.
Building the right thing for the right
people, discover the real problems. What
you might realize when talking to users
is that
you start with you'll see I will tell
you how to make your questions but you
start with something trying to validate
your assumptions to open questions and
you might realize that the problem that
you assumed that they have it's a very
small problem in a big ecosystem of
other big problems that you are not
solving for them. Therefore, for that
little tiny problem they won't use our
product even though the problem exists.
So, this is why you need to talk to them
to see how you fit in their ecosystem
and discover their real problems and you
might
discover that other problems are
more important.
And they will pay money to solve those
rather than something that you started
with.
You go there to validate assumptions or
to invalidate them, it's the same and
you need to fall in love
with the problem.
So,
you need to find this problem space
where to find a problem to fall in love
with so that you can find the right
solution because if you fall in love
with directly with the solution without
validating that there's a problem you'll
get to
to issues.